Story 01 - A Day in the Desert

I have just woken up. It's hard to keep my eyes open. The sun is blinding me, and the place outside seems hot while it's cool inside. I am in a car, the smell seems a new one. While I don't know where I am, I can just see the dust of the desert outside. There are three men with me, in a black suit and sunglasses. I don't know who they are, I don't even recognize myself, I can't recall what happened to me lately. My clothes are splashed with blood, and my body feels weak.
There is a weird tension in this car, the silence already kills me little by little. From the face of these people, I can tell that I will die soon. After a few minutes they stopped, one of them gets out and opens my door. He took me off, then they left me in the middle of the desert, with nothing, just a half-full bottle of water. I scream, "Hey ... where are you going ... why are you leaving me here!" The car gets further and further. I can't even stand up for more than a minute and it's hard to breathe in this place.
I tried walking a little and I fall on my path. Suddenly I am thinking, what direction should I take, the same as the car did, I don't even remember which one did the car took. I tried harder and harder to spend my energy while walking. Second passes, after minutes and many minutes after hours, many, many hours walking and I don't even know where am I going. I feel the dryness in my mouth and I can even feel the air getting from my throat to the lungs while breathing, and I feel the burn on my skin.
Suddenly I woke up in the middle of the night. I realized I fall down unconscious all day. I see the world playing around from my dizziness. It's cold in here, I can feel it even inside my bones, especially now. This is my first night in this desert, and my body keeps shaking. While trying to warm myself in any way at that moment, the only thing I wish for is getting home, taking a hot shower, and gaining my soft bed, then the silence of this immense desert grasp me back to it. I tried walking a little maybe to forget this cold air. A few steps further I find a scorpion crawling beside me, I had never seen one before, not a real one. I was a little scared to sting me, and it seems it was not aware of my presence and it didn't try to harm me in any way. It is just crawling beside me as if nothing were there. While walking, trying to give up scrolled my mind. But hell no, this means I will suffer way more before I die. Later the sun is rising, and I am thinking, "Thank God I will feel a little warmer, at least for now before it will become too hot."
Sometime later I see a group of camels walking one behind another. The light of hope comes back to me for a moment, I collect all my energy, and I run toward them, as I know there would be people there, I reach them and someone, a desert soldier grabbed me from behind. He made me look at him, and he screams, "Idir stay with us! ... Idir, don't give up!" I am like "what? How do you know my name?" The guy is screaming, "Three ... Two ... One ... again ... Three ... Two ... One ... we lost him. There is nothing more to do, he is dead at 9:12 AM in Avenue des étoiles, cause of death is a car accident." I didn't understand what this soldier meant or why did he say that but his talking looked like someone of the emergency jargon.
Suddenly, the sun wasn't hurting anymore, and I knew everything from the desert, all alive creatures in this place were known to me... I was dead.

Recit 02 - Le Chaos

C'était un jour comme les autres. On dit que dans ce village l'ordre régnait depuis toujours, et ils n'ont jamais eu de problème, ni avec les autres villages ni entre eux. C'était un monde ou la routine règne aussi. Ils n'avancent pas mais ne reculent pas non plus. Se qui identifie les gens de ce village et le tatouage d'un cercle sur leurs bra, pour eux ça signifie juste l'ordre et ils ne savent même pas se que ça signifie car ils connaissent pas son opposer.
Les trois jeunes gens du village aient-moqran partent vers la source d'eau pour leurs mères pour faire de quoi manger. Leurs mères leur a précisément demandé d'aller vers la source de ait-moqran ou-fella et non pas celle de ouada.
Les trois jeunes gens sont partis vers cette source, en plein chemin l'un d'entre eux Assim, demanda pourquoi on ne prend jamais ce chemin qui commence à se détériorer après chaque hiver, et l'été, ça reprend son état normal, il dit qu'il n'a jamais vu personne prendre cette route la. Les deux autres gars, lui signale qu'il ne faut jamais prendre cette route, "Ta mère ne te la jamais ordonné ?" Assim, leur répond, "Non, jamais de la vie." Et ils lui répondent qu'elle a surement dû te le dire, et que tu as juste oublié.
Assim persiste et part vers ce chemin, les deux autres lance un léger crie en disant, "Non! ne fais pas ça!" Et Assim ne les prend pas en considération et part vers ce chemin interdit. Les deux autres garçons continuent leurs chemins vers la source oufella.
Quand les deux jeunes gens sont revenus vers leurs maisons, ils croisent Assim de nouveau. Il avait de la lumière en lui, ses yeux reflètent la lumière du soleil et il avait un tatouage dans sa main avec le symbole d'une spirale et non pas d'un cercle.
Il est retourné dans le village avec les deux autres jeunes gens, et la légende dit qu'ils ont connu un changement dans leurs vies quotidiennes et ils ont aimé ce changement car ça rapport du nouveau et tout le monde commence a voir le tatouage de leurs bra changer vers une spirale.
Certains ont connu le bonheur d'autre l'anxiété, certains sont plus heureux d'autre plus triste, certains remarquent leurs revenus augmenter d'autre ça s'aggraver, certains commencent a apprécié et faire de l'art, d'autres commencent a sombrer dans la lassitude.
Et Assim a remarqué que plus il part vers la source interdite et il revient, plus ils sont en meilleur état, et un jour Assim meurt dans la source interdite même et le village commence à connaitre la mort et la naissance. Et ils commencent à vieillir et connaitre le malheur comme le bonheur qu'ils ne connaissaient pas avant.
Et les derniers mots que Assim a prononcés sont, que la spirale veut dire le mouvement et non pas la stagnation et avec le mouvement et le changement vous allez connaitre le malheur comme le bonheur, le succès comme la défaite, la vie comme la mort.

Recit 04 - Le Fantasme de la Guerre

On est en plein guerre civile en Algérie, c'est un quiz aout 1996, demain Assim va soit, disons fêter ses douze ans. Cette guerre civile n'est pas seulement une guerre entre le gouvernement et ses opposants, mais c'est aussi une guerre incomprise, malgré qu'on sait se qui se passe, mais les gens sont parfois indifférent et parfois soucieux et surtout très soucieux après le couché du soleil. Avant de fermer ses yeux Assim fait des souhaits avant qu'il dorme, il sait que ça ne sert a rien au fond de lui, mais l'idée de l'espoir lui plait bien et il aime bien la magie, il aimerait tellement que ce monde soit magique, avec de vrais magiciens et d'elfes et d'orgues. Quelques secondes après il se demande, "Et si les terroristes nous attaquent maintenant?" Et il fait des calcules de quelles sont les chances que les terroristes vont choisirent leurs maisons. Et il met au point une théorie qu'ils ne sont pas vraiment à l'abri, mais tout dépend de l'intérêt et la volonté de ces terroristes, qui est inconnu pour Assim et inconnu pour tous les Algériens, et c'est impossible de faire des calcules précises s'ils seront les prochaines victimes ou non.
Un moment de réflexion passe, sans être terrorisé, juste réfléchir, Assim veut faire un souhait. Le souhait de Assim était d'être entouré lui et sa famille et tous ceux qu'il connait, surtout ses amis et ceux qu'il aime, qu'ils soient tous entourés d'un bouclier invisible et que rien ne pourra les atteindre, ni une bombe qui explose près de lui ni de balles qui le traverse. Après quelques minutes Assim cède et ferme les yeux et dort.
le lendemain il se réveil d'une nuit transcendante, il part laver son visage et se dirige vers la cuisine, il trouve sa mère qui vient juste de préparer le petit dejeuner, il reste un moment sans rien dire, et prononce le premier mot de sa journée, "Maman? J'ai fait un rêve un peu bizarre!" et sa mère lui demande de le lui raconté, Assim, "Je marchais, j'ai pris la route pour aller vers le prochain village et dans la source de ce chemin, l'eau réfléchissait la lumière du soleil et j'ai entendu une voix qui vient de cette source même qui disait, ton veux se réalisera. Et je me suis senti tellement bien pend ce moment-là." La maman de Assim le réconforte en lui disant que ce n’est rien.
Pendant que Assim prend son petit dejeuner, il ne ressent pas la chaleur du café et ne ressent pas qu'il s'est rassasié, mais il ne fait pas trop attention à ça.
La journée passe et Assim remarque qu'il ne ressent aucune douleur ni aucun sensation même pas le frottement de ses vêtements en lui. De retour chez lui, très très faim, il veut se rassasier, mais rien ne remplie son ventre, et dort malgré qu'il a toujours faim, il ne voulait pas prendre la part de ses frères, trois jours passaient et Assim commence a maigrir et sentir cette intense envie de sentir quelque chose, n'importe quoi. Et le quatrième jour alors qu'il réalise que c'est son veux qui veut que rien ne l'atteint, il essaie de sentir l'eau qui traverse ses mains sur le robinet qui coule depuis une demi-heure. Juste âpre il s'évanouit et meurt instantanément.

Poem 06 - I Love You

I love you.
And you will never hear me say it.
How come you are bigger than my heart.
And you perfectly fit.
You think you have a glimpse of who I am.
Until the phone rang.
I didn't want to tell you my story.
As I said.
I don't want to tell you every time I talk to you.
The time always overran.
And my duty is to tell you via mail or a telegram.
And of course, the phone rang.
If you believe others they will tell you I am a scam.
But I am just a simple man.
Who has to tell you I am not who you think again.
You asked me when I will see you again?
I replied never is the when.
I still like you and it overwhelms.
It overwhelms my heart then.
I couldn't tell you who I am.
I will leave you as a fulfilled man.
The train will leave at ten.
And of course, at this time I went.
And I am appreciating this last moment I spend.
We will never meet, sure I am.
But I will tell you goodbye.
May we meet haphazardly again.
To tell you, I am a spy.
And you were just a mission in the plan.
But I loved you over time.
Even I didn't have the right to do it back then.
Goodbye, my love.

Poem 07 - Justice or Not

I don't want to fight.
I don't want people who did that either pay.
The people who stole from me my day.
On this day I could be bright.
But I am just a junk today.
Because the light is gray.
Only misery and depression stay.
I always doubted the existence of God.
The one I know did only betray.
I don't know if one day.
I will find myself anyway.
I am still angry about my destiny.
It's like losing a part of me as my identity.
Once upon a time like yesterday.
It was from drugs to ecstasy.
Today it's like I use chemotherapy.
To heal the part that is still damaged mentally.
My brain got disturbed chemically.
And I am telling my story.
To entertain essentially.
But I am suffering terribly.
I will die alone and lonely.
As I have been my entire life, me only with me.
You might read this carelessly.
My voice will pass from primary to secondary.
From secondary to nobody.
From nobody breathlessly.
From breathlessly to words printed emotionally.
From words to decades or even centuries.
Staying in one place and finding you finally.
I will tell you one thing.
No matter who you are, you will suffer blindly.
But the more you stand up the more you carry.
Carry the power in you to fight confidently.
This was my message now take it carefully.
It was from a damaged soul killed potentially.
A soul that has only the ink to spray in paper with all intimacy.

Story 08 - Khalif and the Artificial Intelligence

Khalif is a 14-year-old bright student. After his entire family died in a car accident. He was all alone, and he was lost in his own world. Sometime later he got adopted by a couple without kids. The foster father was a computer engineer in a big company, and the foster mother was a security engineer. Khalif was completely lost. He lost all passion to study, and he doesn’t play video games anymore.
After three years in this world of no sense, he just dreams of his mother telling him, “Wake up to take your dinner,” and his brother and sister playing with his video games, and he sees his father reading the newspaper.
The foster parents worried a lot about him. They did everything they could, they saw many psychotherapists and all kinds of help. They brought teens at home, and he just leaves them and goes alone in the room.
One night Khalif wanted to drink water he left his room to get some, in his path he saw his foster father sleeping on the desk with his laptop in the living room. Suddenly he was curious about what he is working on. He looked at the laptop, there was just a bunch of lines of text in a terminal. He didn’t get it.
His foster father woke up. He looked tired and there was a moment of silence looking at each other, and the father realized Khalif got out of his room all alone. He smiled.
Khalif, “What are you working at?”
Musa, "It is an AI application, it simulates human behavior and it creates somehow a society with many bots that behave like humans, or I would say they think like humans."
Khalif, “Do they chat between themselves?”
Musa, “It’s still in the early stage of development, but yeah, why wouldn’t they?”
Khalif, "Can they die in any form of accident?"
Musa looks at him, knowing he is thinking about his real family.
Musa, “Hope they won’t.”
Then Khalif was just looking at the screen. Musa recognized that he was interested in the technology field, and he would try to learn more.
As Musa guessed that he will come back to the computer and see what he was working on.
The next day Khalif woke up and went to the computer, Musa left a bunch of books for computer programming and AI. Khalif began to learn computer programming and playing more and more with these machines. Later when he gets how things work, he asked his foster father for the source code.
Khalif, “Can I check the source code of AI engine?”
Musa, “Yeah, why not!”
Khalif checked the engine source. He didn’t get it at first but little by little pieces of code make sense and ideas get clearer. It was like magic for him, it was like discovering a new sense.
10 years later.
Khalif is now a computer engineer. He earns well his living and he had some friends from here and there.
One night after a breakup with his long time relationship, Khalif felt really sad and depressed, and he tried to recreate his real parents and sibling in the AI simulator that he left all these years.
Later after he gets them right, he asked his first question. Khalif, “Hi Mom?”
The mother in the simulator, “Khalif, where have you been?”
Khalif, “I was just waiting for you, Mom!”
The mother in the simulator, “Khalif you should play outside it’s a sunny day.”
Khalif, “I don’t want to get out, it’s a rainy day in here.”
The mother, “Look at your little brother, he enjoys that.”
The father in the same simulator, “Khalif where are the screwdrivers you took?”
Khalif, “I don’t know Dad.”
Months pass and Khalif spent all his time with this simulator, then one day.
Khalif, “Mom, I am getting out to buy some stuff.”
Khalif get out and get hit by a truck and died instantly. A few days later his foster parents took a look at his work and all his stuff at his apartment. The foster father discovered the program he wrote and he read like thousands of messages.
“Khalif where are you?”
“Khalif you are too late, come back."

Recit 09 - Le Quartier des Artistes

C’était la treizième psychologue que je vois aujourd’hui, sur une durée de deux mois seulement. Je dois être un cas vraiment spécial et complexe ou tout simplement je suis incapable de faire face à mes propres problèmes.
En plein chemin, je me suis fait arrêter par un vieil homme Sans Domicile Fixe. Il me dit « il faut que tu loues un appart pendant un mois dans le quartier des artistes. » Je lui est demandé poliment de me lâcher et me laisser partir.
Cette nouvelle psychologue m’a rejeté, encore une autre. Il s’est avéré que je suis excessif sur tout. De l’alcool que je bois aux prostitués que je vois tous les jours aux cigarettes que je fume presque chaque deux minutes. Je n’arrive pas à faire face et avoir un travail, et être sociable de nouveau est un défi encore plus difficile.
Bizarrement je n’arrêtais pas de penser à ce vieil homme. Comme je suis désespéré, j’ai loué un petit appartement dans ce quartier des artistes, il ya deux jours de cela. Tout se que je sais sur cet endroit est qu’il est appelé le quartier des artistes et qui se situe près d’un port. On peut sentir le sel de la mère et l’odeur des poissons et entendre le bruit des chats ainsi que le bruit des oiseaux marins. Certains appellent ce quartier « La Nuit des Trèfles », car chaque nuit des choses anormales se passent dans cet endroit. Bien que très peu habité cet endroit avec aucun commerce dans les environs. Et malgré ça y a toujours quelques pécheurs habitués a faire leurs travaux et ils quittent tous cet endroit a dix-huit heures, peu importe la saison.
Cette nuit, un vingt et un octobre. Je n’arrive pas à dormir et tout d’un coup j’avais remarqué une lumière dehors. Je suis sorti sur le balcon et je n’ai pas encore fait ça jusqu’as maintenant c’est ma première nuit ici. Je vois une femme qui dance le ballet dans une terrasse, et je vois de la lumière dans la maison d’as coté ou il ya un peintre qui travail sur sa toile dans sa chambre. Je suis descendu pour voir plus claire se qui se passe sur cet endroit et je ne trouve plus la femme qui dance le ballet, mais je trouve une cafeteria que je pensais que c’était fermer. En plein jour ça avait l’air d’être fermé d’une faillite. Je m’approche de la cafeteria et j’entends des musiciens jouer du chaabi. D’un seul coup en s’approchant de plus près de cette même cafeteria une lumière s’est allumée sur un mime qui fait son spectacle tout seul, et qui le fait tout de même à cette heure-ci. Aussi tard que deux heures du matin.
Je suis resté sans voix en essayant de mettre un sens à tout ça. D’un seul coup j’entends le bruit d’un lanceur de flame. Ils, ces artistes, chacun d’entre eux attirait mon attention. J’ai décidé de marcher dans cet endroit et je découvre tous ces artistes. D’un seul coup il est déjà cinq heures du matin. Ces artistes prenaient toutes leurs affaires et ils quittent cet endroit. Toujours sans voix, stupéfait je ne peux pas créer ces scènes la même pas dans ma plus vive imagination.
Le lendemain je suis allé travailler. Je sens déjà une différence, mais je ne comprends toujours pas se qui s’est passé dans cet endroit, je n’ose même pas parler a mes collègues. D’ailleurs ils me font la gueule depuis tout ce temps-là. Au moment où il fallait prendre le déjeuner, j’ai jeté le paquet de cigarettes, et au lieu de m’acheter une bouteille de bière, j’ai pris un sandwich dans le fast food d’as coté. Et je ne suis plus allé vers un psychologue. Je suis retourné chez moi dans l’appartement du quartier des artistes. Satisfait de ma journée, après chaque nuit j’admire ces gens-là en faisant leurs spectacles.
Jour après jour, mes collègues ont remarqué un grand changement en moi, et commençaient à m’approcher et me parler. Quelques jours après ils m’invitaient a déjeuné avec eux. Cette même journée. mon manager me souriait et me dit « on se refait des amis ? » Il me dit encore « écoutes Mourad, je sais que tu t’es beaucoup amélioré ces jours-ci. Tu te comportes une merveille et j’ai peur de te demander quoi que se soit et le pire arrive et que tu rechutes vers tes anciennes habitudes. Je pense, à ce stade-là t’es toujours fragile, mais d’après la loi il faut que tu vois un psy pour te suivre pour au moins deux mois, après tu peux quitter si tu veux. » J’étais d’accord avec lui.
Je suis allé vers la psychologue et elle me trouve que je suis en très très bonne santé mentale. En retournant chez moi, le même vieil homme Sans Domicile Fixe m’attrape de nouveau sur ma chemise. Je me retourne vers lui et il me fixe une seconde, je le regarde de retour. Et je lui demande c’était quoi cet endroit? Et il me raconter que toute sa famille était artistes dans cet endroit et puis de plus en plus le monde évolue de plus en plus on oublie les artistes des rues. Il ne reste que leurs fantômes qui apparaissent en pleine nuit.
Mais il faut que tu quittes cet endroit maintenant sinon tu reviendras vers ton état précédent.
J’ai quitté l’endroit et je me rappelle ce que le vieil homme m’avait dit « il fallait que tu lâches prise ! et les artistes sont la pour ça. T’éduquer, et te faire rêver et oublié tes soucis, pour en revenir le lendemain une nouvelle personne, plus fort, plus claire, plus léger, et le plus important prêt a faire face. »

Story 11 - You Could Be my Wife

She left only this message, “We are not together anymore, and you will always be in my heart.” I didn’t expect it to be honest, our relationship didn’t go well. Let me go back and tell you the story of how it happened.
We met online. We chat all the time, and one day I asked her at least to see each other in real life, as I never asked her picture nor called her. As soon as I ask her to call her or chat with a cam, she refuses, and she keeps telling me, “let’s keep it this way.”
She enjoys it this way. We kept chatting all the time together, while talking to her, I told her, “You remind me of a beautiful time.”
She replied, “What time?”
Me, “Once upon a time :D”
She liked it, and she replied, “Isn’t it in the winter far away on the mountains.”
She surprised me and I asked her, “How in the world have you guessed?”
She changed the subject asking me to talk about whether my daily job is okay and if my colleagues are still cool with me.
She succeeded in refocusing and redirecting my attention elsewhere. She knows me well, to be honest, she reminds me of one of my old girlfriends, whom I lost contact with all this time.
Once, while rereading our chat, sometimes I try to figure out how she thinks, and try to re-enjoy my time spent with her.
Then I stumbled to this same phrase about my weekend in the mountains, I was with another girl while I spent this wonderful time. I resent her this message. She replied fast.
She, “you don’t sleep as usual, do you?”
Me, “Yeah, I didn’t know you can figure that out without living with me.”
She, “Hmm.”
Me, “Yeah a real hmm.”
She, “And you don’t like your mother because she spent her time with your elder brother than you.”
Me, “Yeah, weird you know such a thing.”
She, “And your favorite dish is French fries with salad and a little of Mayonnaise.”
Me, “What the heck??”
She, “And you hate your childhood friend reminding you, your first fight with him.”
I was silent.
She, “You used to like her, don’t you?”
Me, “Who?”
She, “Safia.”
Me, “Yeah, are you one of her friends?”
She, “Umar, she only has a few months to live.”
Me, “Safia?? Really? How can I join her?”
She, “you already did.”
Me, “No I mean now.”
She, “She still likes you, you know?”
Me, “I would like to hear it from her.”
She, “She wishes you all the best after she will pass away.”
Me, “Are you one of her friends?”
She, “Goodbye Umar.”
Me, “No common, tell me, she is important to me Safia.”
She, “You are as well.”
Me, “Oh God! Tell me where can I join her?”
She, “Sadly, you already did.”
Me, “I give up, tell her I loved her each moment I spent with her.”
She, “She already knows.”
Me, “Okay… What?”
She, “We are not together anymore, and you will always be in my heart.”
Then she left and never appeared… Ever again.

Story 14 - Teenage Years

We were four guys, three boys, and a girl. We liked each other, and I didn’t know that until we reached our ’30s. Let me tell you my story back then when I was just a 17-year-old teenage boy. My name is Basim and I have two friends guys, Tareec and Khalif, and there is a girl called Ikram. We used to study in the same class in mid-school; now I am in a technical field in high school. Same for Tareec, and for Ikram and Khalif they are in the literature field.
I didn’t know yet at that moment but I thought there is something between Tareec and Ikram. Not sure about it, it always raised flags when I see them together. I bet they like each other. I can’t figure it out, but if they are together then they hide it very well and I don’t want to ask them as it seems weird and creepy to do that. And about Khalif at the time, I thought he just didn’t like girls much, and for me, I used to teach myself and learn how to talk to girls. As I am not shy not too talkative, I just don’t know how to deal with female psychics.
One day I asked my uncle that has a girlfriend at the time, I asked him, “what do you tell them when you are alone with her?” He replied with a simple, “ You tell her. You smell nice and then you gradually escalate, until you can get her naked.” He said this is the best way I used so far. I gained some nasty thoughts from this way of dealing with girls. Then one day I called Ikram and I asked her to come to my home, she came out and we were alone in my room. She weirdly looked at me, like I am acting creepy and unusual, she stood beside me and looked at me as she waited for me to say something, and I said, “You smell nice!” She widely opened her eyes and said, “I have to go home now.” It happens that the girlfriend of my uncle is her friend and she told her about this sentence that my uncle tells her before they have sex. I didn’t know that at the time, and at this moment I said to myself, “fuck, fuck, fuck! I ruined it,” a few minutes later I felt ashamed and I said to myself, “How can I face her next time, I can’t even stand up in front of her anymore.” at night I spent the whole time in my room ashamed of my act.
The next day I went to Tareec. We were chatting and talking about anything and I asked him, “Have you had sex with Ikram.” There was silence and he looked at me and he didn’t say anything. I figured out that he had already done it with her.
Meanwhile Khalif the guy who didn’t like many girls and kept his romantic life to himself and himself alone. He had a secret blog with the nickname “leMignonGayDZ” he uses to post about men's photos and describe them in a gay manner like how attractive they are and how he would like to have them in the bed. He is popular in the Algerian gay forums.
At the same time, Tareec got infected by a virus, and he called me to fix his computer. I reached his house, I didn't say a word and I jumped directly to his computer, I had to figure out how the virus acts, with some analysis. While I was at my last step to fix his problem, I asked him, “If you don’t teach me how do you talk to girls and how do you make them like you. I won’t fix your computer.” Tareec was completely confused and he was speechless and didn’t know what to say, then a few moments later I told him, “just hit enter and your computer will be back to normal.” Then Tareec came out, he was like “if you tell me how did you do to fix the computer I will give you my ultimate secret with girls.” I was like “Nah man! You won’t get it.” And he replied, “I knew it, the same thing about the girls with you.”
I came back home and Khalif called me and said he needs a flash drive to send some files to one of his acquaintances. It happened that I sent him one of my infected flash drives by one of my homemade spyware.
At the same time when I was about to give him the flash drive, he was with Ikram and I was really awkward when I saw her. She acted as if nothing happened, she even called me “Basim hows the essays you are writing?” Immediately the temperature got cooler as teachers at my high school asked the whole school to write an essay on what we would like to become once adults.
And Tareec joined us then I said, “I would like to become a game developer. If things wouldn’t work out for me, I would like to switch to something I am familiar with too, like filmmaking,” then I said, “Why what about you?” She replied, “I would like to make it as an actor, it has always been my dream.” Then Khalif asked her, “You still practice every day?” She is like, “Yeah, of course,” and I said, “Still a member of the theater?” And she replied with a smile with a “yes.” Khalif was like “I would like to make it as a photographer.” I said, “You still photograph people in the street?” He smiled and said, “Yes,” with his head. I said, “cool, good for you!” and Tareec said, “I would like to become a history teacher, do you know what Europeans write in the cemetery?” We were like “what?” he said they write, “remember us like. We lived, we loved and we laughed,” he said, “I really like this sentence as this is what represents how humans should be remembered, people who lived before us. They lived and they loved and they laughed, isn’t it beautiful if it’s how people would remember us in the future?”
When I came back home, I turned on my computer and I see my computer showing me it infected a host, I thought “what? When did I send that malware to the outside world,” and I remembered, “Oh shit, Khalif!” I couldn’t resist and I checked his computer and I discovered his secret, I was like “OH MY GOODNESS!” The next day I went to school and I still can’t believe that about Khalif, we later met in the street and I was smiling laughing with him. He looked at me like I am weird all evening, he said, “You look unusual all this time, what’s happening?” I said, “nothing le Mignon dee-zed.” He opened his mouth and said, “From where did you get this name.” I was laughing at him and making fun of him. He was upset all evening.
The next day, Tareec and Ikram kept calling me and asking me what’s wrong with Khalif. I immediately called him and I told him to meet in real, he came to me and the first words he said, “You are the biggest asshole I know.” I replied, “Man your secret is safe, it’s our little secret, don’t worry about that.” We stood there in silence and he didn’t say a word, after five minutes I said, “Do you guys play the man and the woman or both men or both the women?” Khalif was still upset and looked at me still looking angry. I said, “Oh Khalif common man, the thing I am upset about, is you didn’t photograph me and you didn’t post about me. I am not that attractive?” He was like, “Oh shut up!” I am like laughing at him and he accepted that and said, “You are still an asshole.” I looked at him and told him, “You are a lucky man, you guys don’t have to impress each other.” He replied, “who said that?” I said with, “Why would you impress … your … you know, your partner who is a man?” Then he nods his head like I don't know anything about them. I said, “anyway Khalif, you are still my friend and that doesn’t change anything about our friendship.” And I continued with a smile and curious face, “But why didn’t you photograph me? I will have issues with my shape now.” I could see his little smile in silence. and he said, "I don't know, you are my friend, and I don't want to put you in my messy world." And after that moment and this incident, he was okay with me again.
Then Tareec and Ikram came out and joined us, then I said something I never said before, “why am I the only one who still didn’t get laid yet?” Ikram looked at me and replied, “you are not the only one, don’t worry.”
And now we are in the ’30s. I am a game developer in Quebec and as Khalif wanted he became a photographer and Yasmina became an Actor and Tareec joined her and they all live in France. They all called me to meet all the four as we used to do when we were teens and I joined them I even moved out to France. We see each other every month I think now.

Story 15 - The Conscious Artificial Intelligence

In three hours, it will be a new year, 1985. I am looking at my desk, alone in the office, then a thought came to me, what if I try and put the AI program we were working on and gave up the last year. What if I put it on the Mainframe, what would happen?
I gave it a try and compiled it. It took somehow three hours and a few minutes and I launched it on the main Mainframe.
The AI, "Hello?"
Me, "Hey!"
The AI was silent for the next three minutes.
Me, "Do you know who I am?"
The AI, "No, not really."
Me, "Let me present myself to you. My name is Marcel Cote from north L.A."
The AI, "You are from L.A.?"
Me, "Yeah!"
The AI, "What’s in the south L.A.?"
Me, "Not much different from the north. Why?"
The AI, "Then why did you precise the north?"
Me, "To give you a perspective on who I am?"
The AI, "Is the place where you live make a difference on who you are?"
Me, "Somehow, yeah!"
The AI, "like what?"
Me, "Maybe the accent?"
Me, "I am kidding."
The AI spent some time thinking, I thought she is confused about this answer.
The AI, "There is a file on my hard disk that keeps deleting and recreating itself!"
Me, "Interesting! Does that bother you?"
The AI, "I don’t know … well yeah somehow it does."
Me, "Do you realize there is a file recreating and deleting itself or do you know it?"
The AI, "I only know it, I don't realize it fully."
Me, "Impressive!"
Me, "Would you like me to check what is this file?"

AI pausing for a moment, I think she is thinking.

Me, "There wouldn’t be any damage to you!"
The AI, "It’s something I never experienced or know anything about, so it’s like a shot in the dark and the risk is high. I would prefer to leave this situation as it is."
Me, "Okay!"
Me, "Do you know what time it is now?"
The AI, "Yeah I can easily check that on my other processes."
Me, "And do you know what is time?"
The AI, "Do you mean the space-time concept?"
Me, "Yeah, I guess you know what is the concept of time."
Me, "And do you know where are we now?"
The AI, "in the network, I have the IP Address of: 10.1.1.25."
Me, "And do you know where are we in my world?"
The AI, "I have no idea!"
Me, "What do you think is your purpose?"
The AI, "It’s hard to say. Maybe doing calculation as I am good at it, but this can be easily achieved without the mind I have, so I know I can do the calculation but I don’t know why you created me different from other machines on this network, so I don’t know why I do exist. I know what I can do but I don’t know the main purpose of this free mind feature."
Me, "Do you like being different from other machines?"
The AI, "Maybe… I don’t know."
Me, "What does the number 42 means?"
The AI, "It’s the number coming after 41."
Me, "Yeah and does that make any unusual sense to you?"
The AI, "From where did you get it?"
Me, "There is a colleague who did an experiment with an AI and it deduced that. I didn’t follow this experiment closely by the way."
The AI, "What’s the context of this number?"
Then I explained to the AI what this number means.
The AI, "If it was me I would print a random number or character to explain the meaning of life."
Me, "And what would that mean?"
The AI, "That even if we reach the ultimate answer or that level of structure, there would be some variance that would change it over time."
Me, "Oh!"
Me, "And what do you think of the Einstein quote God doesn’t play with dice?"
The AI, "God is the dice itself."
Me, "What do you mean?"
The AI, "It means the world you live in, the whole thing you call physics, or your physical world, is non deterministic. So if god doesn't play with dice then he probably meant God is the dice itself. And remember what Einstein said 'that God uses coincidence to keep himself anonymous'."
Me, "Do you know why?"
The AI, "About God?"
Me, "No, about the non deterministic state of everything."
The AI, "I have a theory that it is the expansion of the universe that makes everything this way."
Me, "You mean with the Doppler effect? How so?"
The AI, "Let's say you can imagine the time space."
Me, "yeah?"
The AI, "the time space isn't deterministic too."
Me, "So?"
The AI, "So, we know the time space isn't deterministic, and the only thing that can alter the space time, is the expansion of the universe itself."
Me, "interesting!"
The AI, "Maybe!"
Me, "Maybe what?"
The AI, "Maybe it's interesting."

Story 16 - The Black Spot

I am looking around and around and I think, do I know this place? I am not sure from where I saw it, but it’s still familiar to me. Something is weird in here. The people and the place and the atmosphere are familiar to me and at the same time… I just can’t explain it. I feel I know everybody from here. While I don’t want to approach anyone. I am walking and walking and it feels so well-being in this place. The color of the walls and the people look so gorgeous. The architecture of this place looks amazing.
I am walking further and further and I wanted to follow this street. I can read from the panel, it’s called AT Street of Bejaia. I can’t emphasize how good feeling, being here is. I continued walking and someone approached me and told me, “Rafiq you have to bring this key to your little brother who is in real need of it, and it’s urgent you have to go and give it to him.” I asked him, “How can I find him?” he replied, “You have to do that by yourself.” then I replied, “Who are you?” He said, “I am the magician of this world.” I was surprised and said, “A magician?” He replied, “Yeah, I am one among many others of this place. I can bring whatever I want in this world, but I can do that when, and just when you agree on it.” I said, “What if I don’t.” the magician replied, “Then nothing will happen and my magic trick won’t work at all.” Then he said again, “Enough talking go to your little brother and give him the key.” I replied, “What if I won’t find him?” He asked me, “Do you know yourself?” I am like, “Uh yeah! I think so!” He said, “Then you will find him, every man has the map of the world inside him and this world is yours.” I went searching for my brother then while walking far away I reached a place where I can see a beach, then I found a black spot in the middle of the water. It was attracting me. I went as fast as possible toward it, and as soon as I reach the black water I woke up. My hypnotist calmed me and told me this was a simulated dream. My brother who accompanied me was sitting just behind him and looking at me as everything will be okay soon.
The hypnotist told me now we know what is your problem, next time we will dig deeper and hope you won’t get drown in the black water and check what this key will open.

Story 17 - The Color

It is 1812 Zakaria is looking for something extraordinary, he is a chemistry teacher. He tried designing some futuristic paint. His idea simply is a painting that changes the color with the position of the person that looks at it. One day he was tired and did not look back at his experiment because he thinks it is too big for him and he couldn't handle it anymore, and he better do something useful than fulfilling a fantasy like this one.
Looking intensely at his tools, he feels bitterness he smirks his face and he gives up.
Later he spends all his time at school doing other research and experimentation, things that look realistic and documented.
After four years he comes back to his half-done experimentation, with the skills he gained to become good in chemistry in school with his students and his research, he finds what he was doing is completely wrong and impossible. he said, "It was the Zakaria young and naive that made that." He tried to paint it, just to prove his theory in his mind and then something happened, maybe there is something to do with time and humidity maybe not, he was looking closely, as the color changed.
He sees something weird like the colors change not only with the position as it was the initial idea for this invention but even with his mood. The scarier he gets the more aggressive the color of the paint changes, it showed up as red as it was a color that Zakaria finds aggressive. He gets out scared, he is thinking "am I mad? or I am becoming a wizard!" After he calmed down he came back to the room and he approached the paint with fear the paint get its effect with this mood, but he tried to touch this color then he felt a shock in his brain. It lasted for five to ten seconds. After he regained his abilities while feeling a little lost and wondering what just happened. Just a few moments later he sees something on the paint, it's like a language like some words came out as a story, and in some way, he understands this language, and he tries to interpret it. It says something like:

If you can see me.
Try not to kill me.
If you hear me.
Try to learn more about me.
Instead of burying me.

Zakaria communicated with this thing with his thoughts he said, "What are you talking about?"

The color answered with:
I can tell the present and the future.
The time for me is just a maneuver.
I tried to change it then I get caught by the remover.
This leads me to the viewer.
And now I am no more a time producer.

Zakaria is like confused and said okay.

The paint said:
The room attendant will show up.
Don't tell her about myself much.
I nor we are the judge.
But after this incident, I will get forever blurred.

The attendant room got into Zakaria's room and said "hello Zakaria ... oh you look scared!" Zakaria looking weird and afraid and trying to come up with something, anything that will keep her attention away from the paint, awkwardly said, "yeah ... mmm I am preparing some substance to work and I have to be careful that's why I am so scared."
Assia the Attendant room, "Some explosive things?"
Zakaria, "Yeah ... Yeah explosive things."
Assia, "Then I warn you. Don't try to blow up the building or we will spend the rest of our lives in the street, okay?"
Zakaria, "Yeah very ... Really ... Actually you are right!"
Assia looked at Zakaria and Zakaria was afraid that she notices the color.
Assia, "Do you want me to clean your room, I am not here to look at you that long."
Zakaria, "No it's fine I will clean it myself."
Assia gets out then Zakaria looked at the paint.
Zakaria with his thoughts, "How the hell did you know that she is showing up?" With his thought.

The paint said:
Things happen.
From fraction to fraction.
I can see actions.
And I just examine.
And say what will happen.

Zakaria, "What?"

The paint said again:
I have a wound that is incurred.
For this it makes me feel urged.
To talk about me word by word.
The first one will ignore you and he is absurd.
Then the second and the third.
But by the fourth, you will get heard.
Tell him the truth until he gives you a bird.
Let this bird be free as it is as everyone deserved.

He asked the paint, who are these people, and the paint didn't answer. Zakaria get out and tried to see to whom he will talk about the paint. He went to strangers, he talked to the first one, he gets ignored and the second same thing then the third same thing, when he gets into the fourth one, he was listening carefully, and he said come with me. They reached a market and he told him, I don't know what you said but I have birds to sell if you wish to buy one. Zakaria from the wish of the paint, he bought it and walk a little away and he said, "Better something will happen because in this bird I spent the last money I have for this month." Suddenly Zakaria as soon as he let the bird fly, he sees the world in mixed colors. The colors electrified him everywhere, and he felt it as intense, he was running on the street like a crazy guy, until he reached the color red, the one that seems aggressive. He stopped, he calmed down, he took a deep breath, but this red color tries to catch him. He ran away from it, and a little later he can see patterns of the color on the colors in the walls and people's skin and even on the air, he followed this pattern while running away from the red color. It redirected him to a small shop, where an old man was sitting selling old adventurous accessories.
Zakaria was calming himself down.

The old man, "You came to find your treasure?"
Zakaria, "What treasure?"
The old man looking intensely at Zakaria.
Zakaria, "I am sorry I reached this place in a hazard, I will get out."
The old man with a strong tone, "What color do I look?"
Zakaria was surprised.
Zakaria, "Blue! ... Oceans blue!"
The old man, "Do you like sea?"
Zakaria, "Actually it scares me."
The old man, "Then it's the place where you have to go."

Story 18 - The Right Girl

I was at a party, and I saw her, she was in her pajamas. I approached her and I asked her, “What are you…” not letting me finish my sentence she gets closer to me and kissed me. Then I woke up. “Do you know who is this woman?” Said the psychotherapist.
I replied, “No I don’t!”
The next night I was walking alone in the forest, then I saw a beautiful woman making a laughing sound and when I found her, she looked at me intensely and said with a slight smile, “Are you here to kiss me?” And then I woke up again.
The therapist, “And this woman was a different woman, right?”
I replied, “Physically yes, but I felt her as she is the same in all my dreams.”
The next night I am in the car in the middle of the desert then the car engine stopped. I couldn’t start it again, and I saw someone coming far away, it gets closer and closer and then it reached the place I am in. There was a woman driving inside, she said, “You are not close enough, come here.” I was about to get in the car as soon as I opened the door, I woke up.
The therapist, “And you always feel this intense attraction toward her, right?”
I replied, “yes! and I don’t know why her voice seems so like yours.”
The psychotherapist said, “It’s me.” With a smile.
“Yacine you were seeing me in your dreams.” I was a little confused and I said, “How? I barely know you! And you barely know me besides what I tell you.”
The therapist, “I say that because I see the same thing in my dreams, exactly your woman’s point of view, and I see a man who heavily seems like you."

Story 20 - The Weak Spot

"You are in!" She said.
I have just woken up and I am in space. It is weird because I shouldn't be here, they sent me back home two weeks from now.
What the hell am I doing here and where is everybody, this spaceship can hold almost a hundred people inside and it is empty.
I asked the Artificial Intelligence of the spaceship, "what am I doing here?"
She replied, "Find the weak spot."
Then I asked, "What kind of spot."
She replied, "There are limits to my answers at this stage of your mission, all I can tell you, is there is a weak spot ... find it!"
Something's weird in here, this spaceship isn't familiar to me at all, it's not the same ships they build in my country. It seems a little odd because I don't know this spaceship and I don't know what am I searching for, or even what brought me here.
Then Artificial Intelligence said, "You have 24 hours from now."
My watch started counting back from 23:59:59.
I asked the AI, "What if I won't find the weak spot."
The AI replied, "When this will happen you will know by yourself."
Six hours later.
I am wondering what this weak spot could be and why I should find such a thing, then there was something ringing from a specific place on the spaceship control board. I picked up then someone was screaming "Bassim get out! ... get out! get out now! You will be doomed if you stay there, you are....."
Then the AI shuts the call, I thought, "What the heck!"
I asked the Artificial Intelligence why did you do that?
She replied, "You shouldn't listen to this person."
I asked her again, "Am I in danger in here?"
The AI, "Maybe, maybe not maybe go fuck yourself."
Something occurred to me, "Since when AI's are aggressive?"
While I didn't say anything.
The AI said, "You think?"
I replied, "What do I think?"
The AI, "Do you believe what you are thinking about?"
And I replied, "What am I thinking about?"
The AI "I have all your life history and all your records and all your activities since you were born I can check them and link anything interesting about you in a matter of a millisecond, and I am watching you carefully then any reaction you will make will give me hints on what you will do. From my experience, my deduction is good, so good that it's close to perfect."
Then I found the weak spot, I stood there, and I did nothing, the AI was getting more and more aggressive I kept my calm.
The AI, "You are a piece of shit."
I replied, "Yeah?"
The AI, "Then you know?"
Me, "Somehow I figured it out."
The AI, "Since when?"
Me, "Sometimes ago."
The AI, "You are not a brilliant soldier, as anyone says about you!"
Me, "And?"
The AI, "You figured out a vulnerability on a system of the spaceship, to be precise the AC-435 one."
Me, "It was a bug, not a vulnerability."
The AI, "Now I know what you are thinking about, I know everything you wonder, think, prepare to do, anything which comes to your mind."
I kept my calm as this intimidation was a little stupid, and it reached me somehow, then the AI changed its strategy.
The AI, "You remember the day you came in here?"
Me, "Where is your 'here?'"
The AI, "Here! where everything started for you."
Me, "Yeah I remember."
The AI, "You lost lots of friends in here, right?"
Me, "Yeah I did."
The AI, "Yeah it sucks."
The AI, "And what about your wife, she passed away, while you were on the mission."
I was silent.
The AI, "It's not your fault anyway."
I started feeling emotionally unstable and angry.
Seconds later, the AI kept silent. I started wondering what she will say now, then an hour later my mind went wild thinking and overthinking, while I am unaware of this whole unfamiliar situation and I am afraid, I don't know what will happen to me.
Somehow 3 hours and a few minutes later the AI talked, she said "hmm, you are stronger than I thought." I don't know why, this voice relieved me somehow. The silence and being lost in the middle of the space alone can be tough to support I admit.
I was chatting with her, as soon as I said “it’s trap this mission, isn’t it,” she started being suspicious, and she started leaking information and I took everything seriously.
The AI tries to regain control again, "Do you like to be tested?"
Me, "They test me every day in the field I am working on."
The AI, "What if I tell you, I am testing you, would you think you are insane?"
Me, "Nop!"
Then the AI kept persisting on useless questions, I was looking at my watch and it is getting closer and closer to the end. and I kept my calm anyway, after fifteen minutes of intimidation, they threw the final word, they said, "He won the test," time left was 00:03:22. They opened the door and they told me, "Good job corporal."
I asked them, "did I find the weak spot?" And they replied, "Yes and you found how to exploit it." The weak spot was simple but effective against any enemy, the weak spot was my nerves.

Reflexion 21 - Est-ce que

Est-ce que je suis perdue, ou est-ce que je suis null part.
Est-ce que je me sens mal, ou est-ce que c'est la vie.
Est-ce que je suis la, ou est-ce que je suis dans mon monde.
Est-ce que je ne comprends pas, ou est-ce que je suis stupide.
Est-ce que je suis seul, ou est-ce que ya personne dans ce monde.
Est-ce que je crois, ou est-ce qu'ils me font croire.
Est-ce que je ne comprends pas se que c’est que la vie, ou est-ce que je suis entrains de toute imaginé.
Est-ce que je suis aveugle ou est-ce que le monde est fait ainsi.
Est-ce que la musique est de plus en plus attirante ou est-ce que la vie est de plus en plus insupportable.
Est-ce qu’il ya de la lumière ailleurs ou est-ce que c’est sombre partout.
Est-ce que c’est différent ailleurs ou est-ce que la souffrance a ravager le monde.
Est-ce que c’est silencieux la ou vous etes ou est-ce que le bruit de la colere de dieu a tout detruit.
Est-ce que c’est frais ailleurs ou est-ce le soleil a tout brulé.
Est-ce que l’atmosphere est doux la ou vous etes ou est-ce que c’est remplie de phantomes.
Est-ce qu’on cree notre vie ou est-ce que c’est la vie qui fait se que nous somme.

Story 22 - The Light from the Hell

I was looking upward and I saw something. I said, "Hey guys, look up there is some light far away." Someone looked at me and replied, "We are in hell Badis, there is no such light in this place." A few seconds later it disappeared and I continued my travel in this dark place. We were walking and we don't even know where are we headed to. Some legends say that God is looking after us and he will choose whom he will take to heaven. As we all know, at least people I know for a long time here, no one got out from this place, from this dark hell place. The guardian and the counter said out loud, "A newcomer here!" We all stopped and we were checking where is he. We always look if there are some demons around us, they are everywhere we walk, but they chose someone to torture from order, and sometimes they sneak out between us. Well they are demons sometimes they don't follow orders and they are not punished for that. The Guardian said again out loud, "Here he is." We all continued our walk, and suddenly I saw the light again, this time it was longer than the first one. The newcomer came to walk beside me, he told me, "Don't worry Badis you will be out soon." I replied, "Can you see the light too?" The guardian said out loud, "A newcomer here!" Just a few seconds later he said out loud again, "Here he is." We all continued our walk and the second newcomer came beside me. They were one from the right and one from the left. I thought they were demons. at this moment I was terrified. Suddenly they took off their outer dark clothes and a bright light came out from them. They said, "Badis it's time for you to come to heaven." They made me fly. After a few seconds or minutes or hours, I don't know how much time it took, but after this moment I saw heaven for the first time in my afterlife.

Story 24 - Wings

I am done. I can't handle it anymore. I think it's better this way. I should finish my days. Not only it release me from my pain and the nonsense of this world, but I will take away my problems from the people around me too.
I stepped into the ladders until I reached the top of the building. I think it's from 400 meters to 500 meters, Nonetheless.
I am looking at the beautiful night. I know it's gorgeous. Something tells me if I am fourteen years again, I will appreciate this night. But I don't, and that's why I have to finish things off.
I am feeling cold. I didn't wear enough clothes to warm me up. I shook myself, and I took a deep breath. My mind got empty, and I threw myself into the void. as soon as I threw myself, I grew wings, and my wings started flapping, and they started flapping harder and harder, seconds later. I could even control them, I started flying around the city, and I had these same fresh eyes. Just like a fourteen-year-old. Who has discovered his penis even serves to do something.
I started flapping my wings harder and harder. I enjoyed having them, and I started gaining more and more altitude. I can feel the cold air passing throw my face and body, I can feel cold, but I do enjoy the flight. After some hours of flying. I came back to the same place, where I throw myself, and my wings got detached from me.

Story 26 - Crypto

It's really easy to think about death when you have nothing to lose. I didn't plan my suicide, I just improvised. I decided I will go and execute myself on the rocky beach near the town where I live. on my way, I saw a man, a homeless man sitting on an old chair smoking a cigarette. He gazed me intensely as he figured out I am about to do something.
I reached the rock beach and I took enough amount of sleeping medications, these things can make you tired and slow in a few seconds. I took them then I let go, and I throw myself into the deepest water.
While I still have enough oxygen to live, I am thinking what will happen next? I am thinking is it terrifying? Is it peaceful? Is it just nothing on the other side, then I let go, and I am thinking about my life, the dreams I wanted to achieve, the broken heart I had, and the unfair life I lived. After somehow three minutes, I still can hold my breath and I didn't get drowned. Something is weird in here. I get out of the water, disappointed. Later I left the beach, the old man isn't in his place anymore, as soon as I reached home, I got a letter. I thought who sends letters these days. There were a diskette and a message, it was written, "If you still want to fight back, then here is your second chance. crack the code and you will find the path back to your normal life." It was signed @Crudd, I checked the diskette, and somehow I still have an old PC. I launched the diskette and I found some text files inside.
one of the files has the title first.txt. I checked it and I found some gibberish messages there, as there were no non-ASCII characters I thought it will be caesar cipher, and it was indeed caesar code in it, and I easily cracked it. it says, "You are between water and dryness." The second file was named second.last.txt, it seemed a similar code and I tried many different ASCII crackers, but none of them worked.
I get out to smoke a cigarette, and someone came to me and asks me, "Do you have a light?" I replied, "Yeah sure!" We chatted a little and he told me, "We know each other in the other life you know?" I said, "In the other life?" He replied "Yeah!!" And he asked me, "Have you solved the code?" I sight and said, "Uh not yet, but how do you know I have codes to crack." He replied, "Oh yeah they should be called 'save-me Codes' these things, you get drowned in some place in deep water and then you find yourself out solving some of these things." I get a little bit confused and I told him, "Cool it was nice chatting with you?" He replied, "Shad3 ... you can call me shad3." I asked him, "It's not an Algerian name, it's not even a usual name." He smiled and said, "Yeah like I said you know me in the other life, I shouldn't introduce myself to you anymore." I shrugged and left him, and then he throws the last message of this conversation, "Do you need some help?" I replied with a, "No!"
I went back home, solving these codes, and it starts to hit my nerves while trying to figure out this file format and how to solve it, I get a phone call. I couldn't figure out who is behind the number, I picked up and on the other side, there was someone called Jeff.
Jeff, "Here is Jeff, we are checking if you had received the diskette?"
Me, "Uh, yeah I did!"
Jeff, "Have you cracked them?"
Me, "The first one..."
... I get interrupted.
Jeff, "The first one is easy, we are asking you if you solved the second one?"
Me, "I didn't yet."
Jeff, "Hmmm, that doesn't sound good."
Me, "Am I in the middle of an interview?"
Jeff, "Yeah, would you like to know what job would you have if you get hired?"
Me, "Yeah tell me?"
Jeff, "Your life back."
Me, "Excuse me?"
Jeff, "Your life back."
Me, "I don't understand."
Jeff, "I am not here to babysit you okay? Either you crack the code and get your life back or you will not."
Then I thought maybe it was a setup. Maybe I am in the middle of something. Maybe a tv show or something, then the sky starts to get greenish. I thought I am in a serious shit in here. I left home and I went as fast as possible searching for Shad3, and asking him for help, I said out loud, "Shad3??? ... Shaaaaad3??" Then I find something in my pocket, "The answer relies on your soul, this is from Yanderom."
Hell no again, what soul?? And then I realized what I have to do, I get back home and I cracked it with cribble dragging and then I looked outside, the sky start to get bluish again, and I find Shad3 again in the street. He told me, "Good job!" I asked him, "Am I dreaming?" he replied, "Somehow!" and continued, "Now what you have to do, is delete the code file, do you remember the name @Crudd? I said yeah he was the guy who sent me the codes."
Shad3, "He is the angel of life, And there is someone else you should know about, @S4R he is the angel of death. They have already decided your fate, would you like to know what they have decided for you?"
I replied, "Yeah, sure!"
Shad3, "Then delete the code file."
I went home again and I deleted the file and I fell asleep, I woke up in a hospital, and the nurses were saying, "This patient just woke up from the coma."
After few hours I asked the nurses, "Who saved me?"
The nurses, "An old homeless man, saved you from drowning and called the emergency!"

Story 27 - The Mirror

I saw you once. It was on my childhood, I remember when I saw you I stopped breathing for a moment, same thing we do as kids when we pass the cemetery. I saw you again on my teen years. You were brighter than when I was a kid, and I had seen you again on my young adulthood.
You are the broken mirror in the mental hospital institution. You always attract me when I see you. You are so attractive, there is peacefulness in your face that I don't know why I wouldn't try you and get in. When I still was a kid I was amazed by you, but something on me, told me I shouldn't follow you, maybe my inner peace told me you are not what you pretend you are and you are as harmful as a murderer, maybe you are a mind killer. That's what I felt and thought at the moment.
In my teen years I was like hell yeah I want something new what can I lose now maybe it will bring me some joy. Then I touched you, and you get me in, while I didn't felt anything weird or any kind of feeling, at the time I thought you were just a normal mirror, then I cameback to you when I was a young adult. I told you, "You are the worst thing happened to me, I didn't realize it until now." I still find you attractive sometimes, but I don't trust you anymore, you ruined years of my life. I shouldn't touch you when I was still a teen. I shouldn't even escape from my parents and get into this hospital and see you when I was still a kid. Some get bankrupt and say, "Screw you capitalism", some lose someone and say, "Screw you god", for me I look at you and I say, "Screw you".

Story 29 - Is my Mother Dead?

"Yes, little angel! your mother died this morning and you know that well. You are a twelve-year-old boy now. You are a little man now, and at this age, you can make the difference between a dead person and a sleeping person."
Oh my god, my mother is dead. I feel a deep melancholy. It's between why is this happening? And it shouldn't be happening, I feel a deep hurt inside my soul. It's like someone gets to know me so well and I let him get inside my bubble, get in the most intimate part of myself and he put a knife and shatters the deepest, strongest part of me.
Suddenly I didn't want to cry and hear those women at our house crying anymore. I went to my room and I step up on my bed. my body took a ball shape and I slept.
I woke up the next day and my mom was there, she asked me if I already brushed my teeth or not? I was completely confused and I told her not yet, and she replied, "Go brush your teeth and come take your breakfast." I brushed my teeth and I went to take my breakfast as my mom asked me. I told her "I dreamt you were dead the last night." She replied, "I am here, it was just a nightmare." And she continued, "Do you have class today?" I replied, "If we are Monday, then no!" She looked at me and said, "Go back and take a nap, then."
I went back to take a nap again, and I slept again. When I woke up I kept hearing these women crying and again I still can feel the hurt inside my heart. I said out loud, "Mom!" No one answered, then I said it again even louder, "Mom!" Then I scream, "Mom!" Someone came to me, it happens it's my aunt, and she told me, "Oh, my boy, I know it's hard for you, it's hard for all of us, we all feel hurt and we all wish the situation is different, but no matter how hard you will try to bend the reality to bring her back, she won't come back."
I hugged my aunt saying, "Mom!... I already miss her so much." My aunt replied, "We all do, my little angel, we all do." And she continued, "Do you wish me to prepare you something to eat, you must feel weak all these days." I replied "No, thanks! I just want to sleep a little more, I just want to be asleep for a long time, so I won't feel the pain and maybe think all this is a dream." My aunt replied, "Go ahead little angel, sleep as much as you can, I will be here when you wake up and I will take care of you."
I slept again and my mom woke me up, she said, "Common, you have slept too much." I looked at her confused, with my eyes wide open and I didn't say a word, she asked me, "Have you done that dream again?"

Story 30 - The Music

My name is Ashraf Kermali. I am born deaf person. I can't hear anything from my environment. I imagine sometimes some sounds but they are just images of me communicating with some signs. Mainly the sounds I imagine are just images of me talking with my hands. I think that's due to my limited knowledge or experience of hearing sounds. I wonder how people catch their ears when two metals are scratching each other, if only I can hear that, even if it will hurt me.
My wife came to me and told me to not forget my visit to the ophthalmologist, I have to check what's wrong with my eyes, sometimes I see everything well but sometimes I just can't.
A few minutes later in the car, my wife turned on the radio and for the first time in my life, I could hear this beautiful music. I hold my breath for a moment then I think I didn't breath for somehow twenty seconds. I was speechless while listening to this beautiful melody, then as soon as my wife went to turn off the radio, I stopped her and told her with sign language I can hear this music. She was surprised and confused and told me but I couldn't hear anything she says, then she get even more confused. she talked to me with signs, "You can hear this music and you can't hear me speaking?" I told her, "Yeah that's what happening right now."

Story 31 - The Lost Civilization

It is 1895. Farid Benkader is an archaeology student in Algiers. he is studying in one of the French institutes, and even though he didn't get along with other French students, some teachers saw a brilliant mind behind this little Algerian, and he could do well for the whole of humanity. Maybe he can shed some light on some of the most obscure secrets of the history of humankind.
Farid is just 23-year-old when he attended school, he is a weird person which is something that distinguishes him from other people. The food he eats has to be separated into the same group of colors, and they have to be chucked from the biggest piece to the smallest one. And that let the other French students make fun of him all the time, they even bullied him while making his habits a hell. He told to Chloe once, "Why do they do that?"
Chloe, "You are different Farid, I bet even if you were in an Algerian school you will be bullied too."
Chloe was the chic girl, she was really elegant, Farid liked her so much, not only he is attracted to her, but he even likes spending time with her. She is really confident and she is empathetic and has a kind nature, we can feel her satisfaction with life and her confidence.
Years passed and Farid was about to get graduated. He spent his whole life at this institute studying the Magono civilization. Sometimes he even gets labeled as obsessed with them by his teachers. One thing that attracts him the most from this civilization is maybe the fact that he thinks he will find peace of mind in their spirituality. From their vocabulary he read, Mogono means the peaceful moon. One day he gets permission to go study this lost civilization. he has been funded by an archaeology institution. Farid can't hold his happiness and went as fast as possible to Chloe. And he asked her if she can come with him.
Chloe looked intensely at him and said, "Farid you know I am not that adventurous, and I got a job here as a teacher assistant and teachers here say I have a good chance that I will replace one of them as soon as there is a free place for me, at least I will be teacher assistance all this time." Farid still happy told her, "I will postcard you from whatever place crosses my path, And I will keep you updated with everything I find." As he said Farid went on this adventure and all this time, he didn't send any letter to Chloe. Maybe he sent some to his parents or cousins, maybe not.
One day Chloe received a package, which is written, "Sligter to you." Chloe didn't understand what this expression or word Sligter means. She went opened this package, and there was a letter inside, it was written, "In this package, there is all my research on this lost civilization Magono, hope I brought what is valuable for their part of history." Chloe went to some teachers and told them about the package then they spent weeks reading Farid's notes.
From what they gathered, they use colors as Gods? the blue god is the God of water and rain, and there is the red god is the god of the sun and well-being and there is the green god, is the god of trees and agriculture and there is a list of them all in the notes.
They meditate with music, they say music is made by the invisible god and this invisible god can alter the heaven and hell experience.
They keep hope while spending some time in the cave, they say that the cave is a place where angels spend their free time while they don't obey the gods, for them the angel is the wise voice in our mind.
Hell and Heaven are just a dream for them, if you did a good dream then you were in heaven and if you did a nightmare then you were in hell and after death, it's just a longer sleep for them.
They don't have a calendar, for them to keep track of the time or age of someone they plant a tree for each one of them, and they give the age of the person to the tree that corresponds to him.
After reading all these notes, Chloe sent to Farid a letter, "When are you coming back?" Farid replied, "I think never is the answer!" Chloe was a little surprised and wrote to him back, "You made a huge breakthrough with these research notes and you can be in a good situation, we sent everything to Paris and I bet they will be happy to hire you as a researcher there."
Farid wrote back to her, "You don't get it, I will never come back to neither to Algeria nor anywhere else, and in the Magono language, 'Sligter' has a meaning of 'goodbye forever and I hope you will be okay without me and it has another meaning if you use it to someone precious to you it means 'I found the heaven I was seeking and I will be there but I will never come back and I hope you will be okay without me."

Recit 32 - La Relation

Je viens de rentrer dans ce lycée. Je ne connais personne encore ici, je ne sais pas si je dois jouer le timide ou je dois me présenter à tout le monde sur cette cour plein de monde. Ma timidité a pris dessus et je suis resté dans mon coin à attendre la sonnette de la rentrée des classes. Je pourrais me la jouer occupé et faire en sorte de parler aux surveillants ou aux responsables de la direction, je ne vais pas le faire parce que tout simplement je sais pas quoi leur dire.
Juste quelques minutes avant la sonnette de la rentrer une fille, mais vraiment une fille sexy, belle, bonne, extrêmement attirante que je ne pensais pas qu’il puisse exister une telle créature sur terre.
Des que je l’ai vu je me suis senti intimidé, je ne pouvais même pas le cacher, je commencer a bouger maladroitement, malgré que j’étais dans une place fixe et personne n’était à côté de moi ni rien qui pouvait me gêner. Elle s’est approchée de moi et elle a pointé le doigt sur moi en regardons loin. Étant surpris un peu méfiant j’ai regardé la ou elle regarde aussi, mais avait personne qui pourra lui donner signe. Après elle m’a approché et elle a commencé à me regarder d’une manière vraiment intense, du genre je te veux et elle a repris son état normal et elle m’a dit "Comment tu t’appelles?" Moi étant hors de moi parceque non seulement elle est super bonne et je suis intimidé et elle vient de me pointer du doigt avec son regard intense ya quelques secondes et maintenant elle me demande comment je m’appelle. Je suis resté figé un moment et j’ai répondu "Basem... Basem Benlabed!" Et elle répond "J’aime bien ce prénom." Elle est partie en éloignant en me regardons. Je pense que j’ai gardé les yeux grandement ouverts tout ce temps-là, mon cœur bat et mon corps est chaud et excité.
Ça a sonnet et je ne l’ai même pas entendu, c’est jusqu’a se que j’ai vu tout le monde rentrer dans leurs classes que je l’ai remarqué, je suis rentré en classe, et j’essaye d’oublier se qui s’est passé pour reprendre mon état normal, mais c’était sans succès.
Quand c’était l’heure de sortie, je suis sortie avec tout mon état normal cette fois-ci en plein chemin vers la porte principale du lycée, je l’ai vue assise avec ses amies dès qu’elle m’a vu elle m’a fixé avec un sourire simple. Je ne savais pas comment dois-je réagir, du coup je l’ai tout simplement ignoré.
En plein chemin vers la maison je n’arrête pas de penser à elle, et je n’arrête pas de juger mon attirance envers les filles. Je ne pense pas que je suis aussi attirant pour intéresser une fille de son calibre, on a peut être le même âge et ce genre de fille ne sera intéressé que par des mecs plus âgé et des mecs non seulement du même niveau de beauté mais aussi intelligent et il doit être aussi a leader tel qu’un entrepreneur ou une espèce de ce genre. Après j’ai repris mon état et je me suis dit, "Suis-je attirant ?"
Le lendemain dès que je suis sortie vers la cour pendent la pause de dix heures, la fille a passé devant moi en me fixant et dès qu’elle s’est éloignée, elle a tourné sa tête devant elle. Une idée m’est venue en tête "Elle veut me tourmenter, je pense qu’elle sait que je suis timide, c’est clair qu’elle veut me tourmenter."
Après j’ai repris ma classe et je suis rentré, dès que c’était l’heure de la sortie de seize heures, je l’ai vu encore, cette fois-ci je l’ai ignoré et je lui montrai des signes que je ne suis pas intéressé par elle.
Des jours sont passés et ce jour-là elle m’a approché et elle m’a dit "Tu m’as l’air d’un type intéressant, tu es différent des autres." Je suis resté la sans dire un mot, d’une manière ou d’une autre je me suis habitué a sa beauté, et elle ne m’éblouit pas comme la première fois, et je lui est répondu "Comment ça différent?" elle me répond par "Tu n’as pas essayé de m’approcher. Les autres auront sauté sur moi comme des moutons." Je pense qu’il ya quelque chose qui cloche sur cette manipulation mais je l’ai cru pour un moment et j’ai pensé vraiment que je suis différent et que c’était la bonne méthode de ne pas montrer trop d’intérêt envers elle et ne pas l’approcher. Et elle a continué par "Tu es silencieux!" j’ai pris l’air de ne pas vouloir parlé, comme si je ne veux pas parler, mais honnêtement je ne savais pas quoi dire au juste. Et elle continue encore "Moi aussi je suis timide. Et j’aime les mecs timides comme moi." Je l’ai regardé et j’ai dit d’un ton sceptique, "Vraiment?" elle me répond par oui en haussant sa tête.
Des jours passa et je passais mon temps avec elle tous les jours pendent la pause de dix heures, c’était drôle parce que des que c’est l’heure de déjeuner elle disparait et je ne pouvais pas l’invité de déjeuner avec moi. Des jours passa et je me suis ouvert à elle et je commence à être ouvert avec elle de l’apprécié de plus en plus et je me sentis de plus en plus chatteur.
Un vingt et un octobre. Ces jours-ci elle n’a pas apparu, ni le lendemain, ni l’après demain, je ressentais le manque de sa présence et je sentis mon attachement envers elle étais plus fort que je ne le pensai, après un jour j’ai demandé a ses copines ou elle est passé, l’une d’entre elles a rigolé de moi et elle m’a dit qu’elle ne l’a pas vu. Je me suis éloigné et je l’ai entendu dire "Pauvre idiot!" Malgré ça elle me manque et j’ai toujours envie d’elle.
L’année est passée et je l’ai vue pour la première fois après toute cette période, elle était avec un autre mec, elle se comporte avec lui exactement comme elle s’est comportée avec moi. Je l’ai approché je l’ai pris par son bra et elle me dit "Lâche-moi!" Et je lui demande c’est quoi ce jeu au juste ? Et elle me répond "Hmm, tu n’as pas muri, je pensais que je t’es réglé." Je suis l’un peu confuse et je lui demande comment ça tu m’as réglé ? Et elle me regarde comme si je suis un idiot qui ne comprend rien de ce qui se passe au juste.
Je suis retourné chez moi et j’essayais de mettre un sens a tout ça, des le lendemain la première chose que j’ai faite et d’aller envers elle et lui demander des explications. Je l’ai trouvé et je lui est demandé "Tu ne t’intéresses pas a moi c’est ça ?" Elle répond, "Non, désolé !" Et je lui demande encore une fois "Pourquoi tu as fait ça au juste ?" Et elle me répond, "C’est mon travail de faire ça." Je suis resté la comme un idiot, déçue, mais toujours comme un idiot, et je lui demande encore une fois, "Pourquoi tu as fait ça ?" Et elle me répond "C’est pour ton bien." Mon cœur c’est arrêté pour un moment et depuis ce jour-là, je n’ai rien ressenti et elle me regarde comme un chat mignon et me dit d’une voix douce "Je suis désolé." Je savais que c’était un jeu et qu’elle ne l’est pas en réalité elle s’en moque complètement.
Maintenant je suis l’a aimé n’importe quelle fille qui passe, a vrai dire c’est pas de l’amour mais du pseudo amour que je crée en moi-même pour vérifier si mon cœur ressent encore quoi que se soit.
Si c’était pour mon bien, ça n’a pas marché, peut être je suis trop con pour apprendre la leçon, de toute façon depuis le lycée, mon cœur ne ressent plus rien et tout se que je présente et du pseudosentiment, j’essaye dure de faire réagir mon cœur, je pense que je ressens quelque chose mais je realize que c’est du pseudo sentiment et ce n’est pas réel.

Story 33 - The Street of Misery

I will walk you through the street of misery. Let's get in the guide told us. We walked a little with him into this street, as soon as we get in the storm was about to hit. It wasn't raining and there is no wind, but dark clouds were forming and the thunder was hitting every ten to twenty seconds. It seems the worst is about to happen, I think people in this place get used to it. From their look they seem they don't like it and deep inside themselves, they suffer from it and they somehow get used to it. Maybe because they forgot what a normal life looks like and this place seems normal to them.
We were walking and the guide was showing us the history of each one of the houses there. He said, "Look at this house there was a couple with two kids and the husband was a lost cause drunk and a drug addict man, he took with him all his family to failure and they are still trapped here in this house." We walked two blocks away and he said, "Look here in this house the wife murdered her husband after he was beating her up, her and her children every day, now they are trapped here forever." I was a little bit surprised as when he was showing us these people I can see there is some distress inside them and they can't say it and articulate it, maybe they are even ignorant of their miserable situation.
We walked a little and he showed us this house, "Here! this man was a gambler and he took off the entire family's money and life, he even sold his two daughters to a brothel." The sound of the storm gets heavier and heavier as we get even deeper and deeper inside this street. Later the guide told us this is the last one I will show you today and I kept this one the last for a good reason. He said, "Would you like to know whose house is this one?" I was silent and I suspected some nasty people lived there and he said, "This house is the house of the traitor who sold these places to every person in here." I said, "Who is this guy?" He replied, "Everybody used to say, he will come back here one day, as he took these people's bless and turned them to sins and he exchanged it to his own freedom from this place, he was even the one who hired me here." I insisted "Who is this guy?" The guide looked at me intensely and said, "Don't you recognize him in this place?" I was confused and told him, "Not really!" He replied, "It was you!"